<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-11-09T22:38:11-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">My Blogs</title><subtitle>A personal website for publishing blogs and other tidbits. Powered by Jekyll and Github Pages.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Update</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/11/09/update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Update" /><published>2021-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/11/09/update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/11/09/update.html">&lt;h1&gt;Update&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, sorry I haven’t been posting. I’ve been busy learning! I’ve helped write a Python API Library (exciting stuff), add a few docker containers (Jellyfin is great!), and rice my computer a bit.
I used to run i3-gaps, but I wanted to try a non-tiling WM or DE. I installed KDE which, while a little bloated for my taste, was very nice. Tinkered with the themes and Konsole. 
However, I wanted to give Openbox another try. I had tried Openbox before, but did not realize how to use it. I was confused by the black screen and the only menu being the right click.
I customized the rc.xml file to add the familiar i3 bindings. Added a nice looking polybar, and made it look like this!. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/openbox.png&quot; alt=&quot;desktop-screenshot&quot; /&gt;
I also watched &lt;em&gt;Serial Experiments Lain&lt;/em&gt; which was very enlightening. Big fan. &amp;lt;p style=&quot;opacity: 0;&quot;&amp;gt;Let’s All Love Lain!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
I’ll add a few more posts detailing what I’ve done. However, I may just abandon this blog, and keep everything on my brand new deepdepths.online.
I’m getting sick of adding more *.deepdepths.online dns records. See you later&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zack</name></author><summary type="html">Update Hello, sorry I haven’t been posting. I’ve been busy learning! I’ve helped write a Python API Library (exciting stuff), add a few docker containers (Jellyfin is great!), and rice my computer a bit. I used to run i3-gaps, but I wanted to try a non-tiling WM or DE. I installed KDE which, while a little bloated for my taste, was very nice. Tinkered with the themes and Konsole. However, I wanted to give Openbox another try. I had tried Openbox before, but did not realize how to use it. I was confused by the black screen and the only menu being the right click. I customized the rc.xml file to add the familiar i3 bindings. Added a nice looking polybar, and made it look like this!. I also watched Serial Experiments Lain which was very enlightening. Big fan. &amp;lt;p style=&quot;opacity: 0;&quot;&amp;gt;Let’s All Love Lain!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; I’ll add a few more posts detailing what I’ve done. However, I may just abandon this blog, and keep everything on my brand new deepdepths.online. I’m getting sick of adding more *.deepdepths.online dns records. See you later</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">School Days</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/30/school-notice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="School Days" /><published>2021-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/09/30/school-notice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/30/school-notice.html">&lt;h1&gt;School Days&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, I haven’t posted in a month. If anyone’s following this, (which I doubt), I’ve been busy with other things. I have, though, got some new things set up on my server.
Welcome to Nullboard! &lt;a href=&quot;https://nullboard.io/preview&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;
It’s really quite cool. Check out its Github.
It’s a small noteboard made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apankrat&quot;&gt;Alexander Pankratov&lt;/a&gt;
It works very well as a kanboard, and it’s all in localstorage so you can self host it. 
On my Mac, I have it running on localhost:80 and there’s a dockerized version on my server (board.deepdepths.online). Though, the localstorage feature is annoying if you’re using multiple devices. There is also a auto-backup feature, but only for Windows. I’m sure though it’s not too hard to develop for Linux. It seems to consist of a few api calls. I’d love to try working on it, but the html file has a lot of JS and CSS that I’m not experienced enough to understand. (Who uses letter variables?? Just kidding, I know its a higher level of thinking).
In other news, I’m starting to learn Go.
I’ll try to post more often. 
Also, I might add Disqus if there are any readers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zack</name></author><summary type="html">School Days So, yeah, I haven’t posted in a month. If anyone’s following this, (which I doubt), I’ve been busy with other things. I have, though, got some new things set up on my server. Welcome to Nullboard! Link It’s really quite cool. Check out its Github. It’s a small noteboard made by Alexander Pankratov It works very well as a kanboard, and it’s all in localstorage so you can self host it. On my Mac, I have it running on localhost:80 and there’s a dockerized version on my server (board.deepdepths.online). Though, the localstorage feature is annoying if you’re using multiple devices. There is also a auto-backup feature, but only for Windows. I’m sure though it’s not too hard to develop for Linux. It seems to consist of a few api calls. I’d love to try working on it, but the html file has a lot of JS and CSS that I’m not experienced enough to understand. (Who uses letter variables?? Just kidding, I know its a higher level of thinking). In other news, I’m starting to learn Go. I’ll try to post more often. Also, I might add Disqus if there are any readers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Docker is Awesome (Another Rant)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/30/docker-rant.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Docker is Awesome (Another Rant)" /><published>2021-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/30/docker-rant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/30/docker-rant.html">&lt;h1&gt;Docker is Awesome (Another Rant)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just love Docker. I don’t know why. It’s the normie in me. There’s a desire for things to just work. A desire for something to do something well and conveniently.
Docker just works, and it’s awesome. Now, I know that just pulling docker containers is taking the fun out of installing packages and managing config files, but I like how quickly things go.
No more waiting for things to compile or researching the documentation, you can just set an environment variable or two and let the container do its magic. 
Of course, the more complex the container is, the more work is required. The docker-compose file for my *arr stack is convoluted, to say the least. 
I am just a big fan of it, the fact that containers are so easy to maintain, update, and manage. 
For example, I just did somthing today incredibly easily. 
I set up a komga ODPS server and downloaded 200~ comics. Now, I can use an ODPS client and read all of my preferred comics on the go. It was pretty simple.
All I had to do was run a compose file for Komga. Here’s mine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;version: '3.3'
services:
  komga:
    image: gotson/komga
    container_name: komga
    volumes:
      - type: bind
        source: ./komga/config
        target: /config
      - type: bind
        source: /mnt/comics
        target: /data
      - type: bind
        source: /etc/timezone
        target: /etc/timezone
        read_only: true
    ports:
      - 8080:8080
    user: &quot;1000:1000&quot;
    #environment:
            #      - &amp;lt;ENV_VAR&amp;gt;=&amp;lt;extra configuration&amp;gt;
    restart: unless-stopped
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple, mostly copied from the github page. 
Then, I used another docker container called “comic_dl” which allowed me to download entire comics from sites like readcomicsonline.li.
comic_dl only downloads jpgs (thankfully, in numbered order) and komga accepts pdfs not jpgs. So, just use some imagemagick. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;convert *.jpg comic.pdf&lt;/code&gt;. 
Now, all I do is write a simple Bash script which uses takes a link, downloads the jpgs, converts them into a pdf, and removes the originals. 
However, copy and pasting hundreds of links from readcomicsonline.li would be annoying. If only there was some way to extract info from a website in an automated manner…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used a python script, which (with some vim editing) provided an entire list of links that I could download.
So, I just let it run and it downloaded a ton of files, nicely formatted for komga, and komga takes care of the rest. 
That’s why I love docker.
Because with docker, I can do a lot more&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zack</name></author><summary type="html">Docker is Awesome (Another Rant)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hyperborean!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/24/Hyperborean!.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hyperborean!" /><published>2021-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/24/Hyperborean!</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/24/Hyperborean!.html">&lt;h1&gt;Hyperborean!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I’m spending a short vacation in Canada! Having fun up here. I’ve always liked the cold.
Anyways, in more interesting news, I’m considering doing the switch to Nginx. I’ve always used Apache2 for my webserver, but now it’s feeling outdated. I know it’s not outdated but the syntax for Nginx seems more modern. It’s also much more lightweight, and it would run better on my ancient server. I can even just use nginx proxy manager as a container, since all I’m really using Apache for is as a reverse proxy. Nginx, however, is the more recommended reverse proxy, and I would like to use it for the future. I am afraid of the change though. I have multiple configuration files, and I would have to rewrite them in nginx. I hate repeating myself. I know though it’s probably for the best. There’s also just the option of setting up nginx as a reverse proxy in docker-compose. I would have to combine all the docker-compose files in one giant one. This way, I can just add different networks for different services (or I guess I could keep them all in one) and have traefik or nginx manage them. Traefik seems interesting, but difficult. Its website says otherwise but I don’t trust what I’ve read. Also, I’m afraid of breaking the compose files by merging them. It would be nice though. Anyways, I’ll keep any readers posted. Literally.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zack</name></author><summary type="html">Hyperborean! So, I’m spending a short vacation in Canada! Having fun up here. I’ve always liked the cold. Anyways, in more interesting news, I’m considering doing the switch to Nginx. I’ve always used Apache2 for my webserver, but now it’s feeling outdated. I know it’s not outdated but the syntax for Nginx seems more modern. It’s also much more lightweight, and it would run better on my ancient server. I can even just use nginx proxy manager as a container, since all I’m really using Apache for is as a reverse proxy. Nginx, however, is the more recommended reverse proxy, and I would like to use it for the future. I am afraid of the change though. I have multiple configuration files, and I would have to rewrite them in nginx. I hate repeating myself. I know though it’s probably for the best. There’s also just the option of setting up nginx as a reverse proxy in docker-compose. I would have to combine all the docker-compose files in one giant one. This way, I can just add different networks for different services (or I guess I could keep them all in one) and have traefik or nginx manage them. Traefik seems interesting, but difficult. Its website says otherwise but I don’t trust what I’ve read. Also, I’m afraid of breaking the compose files by merging them. It would be nice though. Anyways, I’ll keep any readers posted. Literally.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Struggles With Self-Hosting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/18/my-struggles-with-selfhosting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Struggles With Self-Hosting" /><published>2021-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/18/my-struggles-with-selfhosting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/18/my-struggles-with-selfhosting.html">&lt;h1&gt;My Struggles With Self-Hosting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to set up a homelab is hard when you don’t have any income and you’re the only one who knows what you’re talking about. I managed to get my father’s old PC to convert it into a Linux server. Before, I had only used WSL and Linode servers. I watched a NetworkChuck video (in which he says you can get a Linode server free for a year &lt;em&gt;which is false&lt;/em&gt;) and decided to get a Linode server. I only used it to get familiar with Linux, and now I mostly work on my dualbooting 8-year old laptop. Still, the old PC is useful. It’s the first pure Linux machine I got. I started running some docker containers on it and it worked perfectly. Except for Plex. It’s way too old for Plex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Setting up a website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I set up my own website with this server. It’s located &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepdepths.online&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You probably knew that though. “deepdepths.online” is all hosted on my server except for “myblog.deepdepths.online” which is from Github Pages. Still, this GH-Pages site is relatively new. I work with Apache2 to host everything. It also serves as a nice reverse-proxy. (Speaking of reverse proxies, I’m getting &lt;s&gt;a new&lt;/s&gt; an old server to run VMware ESXI. It’ll run a Kemp load-balancer &amp;amp; reverse-proxy) I like working with Apache, but still regret not going with NGINX. It certainly seems to have its advantages. Still, I don’t want to rewrite everything in NGINX. &lt;b&gt;D&lt;/b&gt;on’t &lt;b&gt;R&lt;/b&gt;epeat &lt;b&gt;Y&lt;/b&gt;ourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Setting up a Samba Share&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had some trouble with Samba shares before. During my school year, I only had a Mac to work with. I managed to find a workaround to the many, many restrictions the school put on them. They didn’t allow opening the Terminal app, but they did allow Pycharm, which can open an integrated terminal. That’s actually how I started learning Bash, the terminal, and Linux. Technically, I learned some Unix before I learned Linux. Still, I was obsessed with the terminal. I started looking up guides for it. Eventually, I learned the distinction between shells, terminal emulators, and the OS. That’s how I fell in love with Linux. (Getting off track though) Anyways, I learned about SSH and VPS. I got a free Linode server and followed a guide to start a Samba share. Back then, it seemed daunting. The /etc directory? config files? user permissions? What were those? Now it’s simple. I still want to see how to expose my Samba share to the net. Only my media directory though, obviously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Setting up a mail server&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the reason I wanted to make this post. I have been trying to set up a mailserver ever since I realized I could do that with my server. I would mess with Dovecot and Postfix. I followed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9zP7qooM4pY&quot;&gt;Luke Smith’s tutorial&lt;/a&gt; to automatically configure these (which I thought was a godsend). Unfortunately, for some darn reason, they would not work. I looked into &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;journalctl -xe&lt;/code&gt; and only saw blocked ports. Port 25 was not reachable was what I figured out. I foolishly assumed that this was &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; fault. I thought my server’s port 25 couldn’t be reached. I abandoned the project at this point. I thought there was something wrong internally with my firewall that I couldn’t figure out. 
Later on, actually yesterday, I found Mailcow. It was the real godsend as it has dovecot and postfix pre-configured in &lt;em&gt;&lt;b&gt;Docker containers!!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/em&gt;As you might know, I love anything docker-ized. I immediately started the docker-compose on my server and immediately ran into problems. The mailcow documentation is slightly lacking, as I thought the preconfigured IP range was ok. However, you need to change it to your local IP network range (ex. 192.168.1.0/24). 
After figuring that out (20 min), I couldn’t reach the custom ports I designated for Mailcow’s web UI. It seemed to be a backend problem and that stopped me in my tracks for a while. Poring through the docker logs, I deduced that it wasn’t even making a connection to the port. Perhaps something was blocking it? I recalled that the mailcow documentation said that UFW could cause problems. I disabled it and sure enough, I could access the Web UI. While configuring mailcow, I ran into the same problem where port 25 wasn’t connecting. I then realized. My ISP blocks port 25. No wonder. I gave up at that point. My only options to self host a server was from a VPS, which I would have to pay for. I don’t have income for that. Too bad. 
I’m looking to set up a gemini capsule now, and an XMPP server or join Mastodon, though I’m probably not going to host my own instance. Thanks for reading through this incoherent rant. I do this so I can get my thoughts straight on this. See ya&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zack</name></author><summary type="html">My Struggles With Self-Hosting Trying to set up a homelab is hard when you don’t have any income and you’re the only one who knows what you’re talking about. I managed to get my father’s old PC to convert it into a Linux server. Before, I had only used WSL and Linode servers. I watched a NetworkChuck video (in which he says you can get a Linode server free for a year which is false) and decided to get a Linode server. I only used it to get familiar with Linux, and now I mostly work on my dualbooting 8-year old laptop. Still, the old PC is useful. It’s the first pure Linux machine I got. I started running some docker containers on it and it worked perfectly. Except for Plex. It’s way too old for Plex.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mailcow Is What I Need!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/17/mailcow-is-what-i-need.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mailcow Is What I Need!" /><published>2021-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/17/mailcow-is-what-i-need</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/17/mailcow-is-what-i-need.html">&lt;h1&gt;Mailcow Is What I Need!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good morning, everyone. So, I forgot to post yesterday again. I spent all day at the Big Apple. Very fun, there’s a restaurant called Clark’s that has good breakfast. Anyways, yesterday, I was researching how to style the minima theme for Jekyll, and I came across someone’s jekyll blog.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.slowb.ro/mailcow-email-migration-from-postfix-dovecot-spamassassin/&quot;&gt;Slowbro Blog&lt;/a&gt;.
This is Slowbro Blog, a blog owned by someone with a lot more experience than me.
Anyways, this blog post (linked above) talks about a &lt;em&gt; dockerized working-out-of-the-box email service&lt;/em&gt;. Better words have never been read. I have struggled for some time now trying to set up my own email server on my one server. (my one server is an old PC someone gave me which actually quite good at running Docker containers but nothing else). I read through the documentation and it seems quite simple. Today, I’ll just apply some updates to my server and setup the docker-compose file. Hopefully, all goes well. 
If I get it up and running by today, I’ll post again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zack</name></author><summary type="html">Mailcow Is What I Need! Good morning, everyone. So, I forgot to post yesterday again. I spent all day at the Big Apple. Very fun, there’s a restaurant called Clark’s that has good breakfast. Anyways, yesterday, I was researching how to style the minima theme for Jekyll, and I came across someone’s jekyll blog. Slowbro Blog. This is Slowbro Blog, a blog owned by someone with a lot more experience than me. Anyways, this blog post (linked above) talks about a dockerized working-out-of-the-box email service. Better words have never been read. I have struggled for some time now trying to set up my own email server on my one server. (my one server is an old PC someone gave me which actually quite good at running Docker containers but nothing else). I read through the documentation and it seems quite simple. Today, I’ll just apply some updates to my server and setup the docker-compose file. Hopefully, all goes well. If I get it up and running by today, I’ll post again.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Customizing LightDM</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/16/customizing-lightDM.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Customizing LightDM" /><published>2021-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/16/customizing-lightDM</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/16/customizing-lightDM.html">&lt;h1&gt;Customizing LightDM&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I forgot to post yesterday because I went tubing with my family. Fun, but tiring. Yet, also relaxing at the same time. Anyways, today I managed to configure LightDM so that it would autostart i3-gaps on login. I also put an Alena Aenami wallpaper on it. Her work is very beautiful and will always be my wallpapers (unless I find something better which I doubt). This is the wallpaper in question.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/aenami-wallpapers/alena-aenami-where-we-were.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alena-aenami-where-we-were&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is actually my first time putting an image in a Jekyll post. Hopefully, it renders right. I’m off on my way to the city, I’ll see you guys tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zack</name></author><summary type="html">Customizing LightDM So, I forgot to post yesterday because I went tubing with my family. Fun, but tiring. Yet, also relaxing at the same time. Anyways, today I managed to configure LightDM so that it would autostart i3-gaps on login. I also put an Alena Aenami wallpaper on it. Her work is very beautiful and will always be my wallpapers (unless I find something better which I doubt). This is the wallpaper in question.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/14/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Post" /><published>2021-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/14/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/14/first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on my blog site! This is powered by Jekyll and Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zack</name></author><summary type="html">This is my first post on my blog site! This is powered by Jekyll and Github Pages.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Real Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/14/first-real-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Real Post" /><published>2021-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/14/first-real-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/14/first-real-post.html">&lt;h1&gt;First Real Post&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this is my first real post on Jekyll. I’m learning the basics of Jekyll and Github Pages. 
I already wrote some bash scripts to automate the posting process and the pushing to Github. I’m actually feeling quite tired. 
My head isn’t working at full capacity. I didn’t get great sleep last night and I spent all day learning this. My brother’s watchin TV, I might as well join him.
I don’t know how Vim lines work. If I write on a line for too long, does Jekyll auto reformat it? I’ll figure out tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zack</name></author><summary type="html">First Real Post So, this is my first real post on Jekyll. I’m learning the basics of Jekyll and Github Pages. I already wrote some bash scripts to automate the posting process and the pushing to Github. I’m actually feeling quite tired. My head isn’t working at full capacity. I didn’t get great sleep last night and I spent all day learning this. My brother’s watchin TV, I might as well join him. I don’t know how Vim lines work. If I write on a line for too long, does Jekyll auto reformat it? I’ll figure out tomorrow.</summary></entry></feed>