<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ignition-ctrl.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ignition-ctrl.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-14T19:23:01-04:00</updated><id>https://ignition-ctrl.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">My Blogs</title><subtitle>A personal website for publishing blogs and other tidbits. Powered by Jekyll and Github Pages.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">First Post</title><link href="https://ignition-ctrl.github.io/2021/08/14/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Post" /><published>2021-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://ignition-ctrl.github.io/2021/08/14/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ignition-ctrl.github.io/2021/08/14/first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on my blog site! This is powered by Jekyll and Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zack</name></author><summary type="html">This is my first post on my blog site! This is powered by Jekyll and Github Pages.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firstrealpost</title><link href="https://ignition-ctrl.github.io/posts/2021/08/14/firstrealpost.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firstrealpost" /><published>2021-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://ignition-ctrl.github.io/posts/2021/08/14/firstrealpost</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ignition-ctrl.github.io/posts/2021/08/14/firstrealpost.html">&lt;p&gt;So, this is my first real post on Jekyll. I’m learning the basics of Jekyll and Github Pages. 
I already wrote some bash scripts to automate the posting process and the pushing to Github. I’m actually feeling quite tired. 
My head isn’t working at full capacity. I didn’t get great sleep last night and I spent all day learning this. My brother’s watchin TV, I might as well join him.
I don’t know how Vim lines work. If I write on a line for too long, does Jekyll auto reformat it? I’ll figure out tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zack</name></author><category term="posts" /><summary type="html">So, this is my first real post on Jekyll. I’m learning the basics of Jekyll and Github Pages. I already wrote some bash scripts to automate the posting process and the pushing to Github. I’m actually feeling quite tired. My head isn’t working at full capacity. I didn’t get great sleep last night and I spent all day learning this. My brother’s watchin TV, I might as well join him. I don’t know how Vim lines work. If I write on a line for too long, does Jekyll auto reformat it? I’ll figure out tomorrow.</summary></entry></feed>